#### **Harish Achar**

Bengaluru, KA, India | +91 8892696887 | @harishvishwakarma.d.n@gmail.com | @linkedin |

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Productive SDET with 5.9 years of experience, curious to work on innovative technologies and ideas. committed to confirming proper functionality and usability of software products before release. Plans test schedules and strategies according to project scope and delivery dates and monitors and tracks bug resolutions.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, SQL (MS-SQL, MySQL), JSON

Testing Frameworks: Pytest, List Framework(Dell's internal), Storage-SVT Framework(HPE's internal)

**DevOps and API Tools**: Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Postman, Jenkins

Cloud: AWS, Azure Cloud

**Operating systems**: Windows Desktop, Windows Enterprise Server, Linux Desktops(Debian, Arch and Redhat derivatives) and

RHEL

**Domains**: Storage (SAN and NAS) and CNAPP (cloud-native application protection platform)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Sr.Software development Engineer in Test** | Calsoft.Inc

June 2023 -Present

- Worked on system testing to make sure product builds/releases are stable in different OS. Triaging the test results and reporting/tracking defects
- Involved in Automation. Contributing to current test case archive, writing automated tests, enhancing the current tests maintaining tests and also involved in code reviews.
- Fixed the defective test cases that increased the pass percentage to 30 percent and Implemented new flow in common test flow which decreased execution time about 20 percent

## **QA Automation engineer** | Aqua security

Oct 2021 - June 2023

- Built automated test scripts to handle repetitive software testing work using pytest (testing framework based on python)
  with maintenance.
- Involved in End to End Testing, Test case creation, Testing them manually, maintaining and planing and customer scenarios.
- Developed/fixed more than 100+ test scripts which saved more than 30 percent release efforts compare to previous release.

## **Quality Assurance Automation Engineer** | Mphasis Pvt ltd

June 2018 - Oct 2021

- Worked on Storage Technology (SAN, iscsi) for HPE Enterprise servers. Gathered data on integration issues and vulnerabilities, reported findings and recommended improvements
- Developed and executed QA test cases, built scripts using python for automated software maintenance. Kept scripts and test cases updated with current requirements
- Upgraded whole framework/tests from old python 2.7 to python 3 and Developed a python tool, which provides end to end connection of the storage n/w from Storage device, switch to management Hardware (OneView component)
- Developed a python tool, which provides end to end connection of the storage n/w from Storage device, switch to management Hardware (OneView component)

## **PROJECTS**

# OneFS from Dell @ Calsoft | AWS Cloud, System testing, Docker, Linux, Python, Kubernetes, NAS

- The OneFS file system is a parallel distributed networked file system designed by Isilon Systems. It serves as the foundation for the Isilon Scale-out Storage Platform.
- More about Dell's OneFS @File system structure | PowerScale OneFS Technical Overview | Dell Technologies Info Hub

# **Kubernetes Security Posture Management (KSPM)** | End to End testing, Docker, Linux, Python, Pytest, Kubernetes

- Kubernetes Security Posture Management is a set of tools and practices to automate security and compliance across K8s clusters.
- More about KSPM @ KSPM

# **HPE OneView** | Python, SAN, Virtualization, Hyper-V, ESXi

- Integrated IT infrastructure management software that automates IT operations, HPE OneView simplifies infrastructure lifecycle management across compute storage, and networking.
- More about HPE OneView @HPE OneView

#### **EDUCATION**